<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Machine Learning on Raol.io</title>
    <link>http://example.org/tags/machine-learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Machine Learning on Raol.io</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://example.org/tags/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning in Azure. Publishing.</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/machine-learning-in-azure-publishing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/machine-learning-in-azure-publishing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;http://example.org/2014/07/21/machine-learning-in-azure/&#34;&gt;previous&lt;/a&gt; post I explained how to create new
Azure machine learning experiment and how to use linear regression to make predictions.
The experiment is pretty cool itself as any other one, but there is one minor problem with it.
It&amp;rsquo;s totally useless. Oh, you certainly can open it up and run all steps manually each time you need
to predict profit (I&amp;rsquo;m still talking about previous post with synthetic experiment and synthetic dataset)
based on city population, but, agree, it&amp;rsquo;s not very suitable. It would be nice if you had a way
to store your trained model and supply data you need to analyze, and get back results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning in Azure.</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/machine-learning-in-azure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/machine-learning-in-azure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a really long pause between this post and previous one, but I hope to get pace and write more frequently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time we will review new Azure Machine Learning service that was announced recently and will solve that &amp;ldquo;boring&amp;rdquo;
linear regression task (from my previous posts) using the ML service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linear regression with scikit learn</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/linear-regression-with-scikit-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/linear-regression-with-scikit-learn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since the last post was written. So it&amp;rsquo;s time to create new one. I know, I promised to explain
how to choose $ \alpha $ parameter and why it matters, but not this time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning with python. Linear regression. Part 2</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/machine-learning-with-python-linear-regression-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/machine-learning-with-python-linear-regression-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the first article on linear regression I promised to show how to do it better,
so this post will be about truly scientific approach to the problem. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry if you
don&amp;rsquo;t get it off hand. Honestly speaking it took some time for me to figure out what&amp;rsquo;s going on
and even now from time to time I take some paper and draw matrices/vectors to be sure I&amp;rsquo;m doing
everything right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine learning with Python. Linear regression. Part 1</title>
      <link>http://example.org/post/machine-learning-with-python-linear-regression-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/post/machine-learning-with-python-linear-regression-part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m taking cool &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/course/ml&#34;&gt;Machine Learning&lt;/a&gt; class at Coursera, so to get better understanding of the material,
decided to write a series of blog posts about it. As it clear from the post title, I&amp;rsquo;m going to explain what linear regression is and how it works.
I don&amp;rsquo;t like to read long-long posts because somewhere in the middle I can&amp;rsquo;t get rid of feeling that the beginning of the post became vague and most of
facts were forgotten. So it&amp;rsquo;s going to be short and painless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>